<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Steve Rubin's blog @ Berkeley EECS</title>
	<link href="https://ssrubin.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://ssrubin.com"/>
	<updated>2015-06-16T20:49:13.333Z</updated>
	<id>https://ssrubin.com</id>
	<author>
		<name>Steve Rubin</name>
		<email>srubin@cs.berkeley.edu</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>speecheditor: an audio story editing tool</title>
			<link href="https://ssrubin.com/posts/speecheditor-an-audio-story-editing-tool.html"/>
			<updated>2015-01-29T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>https://ssrubin.com/posts/speecheditor-an-audio-story-editing-tool.html</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;#39;ve released our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucbvislab.github.io/speecheditor&quot;&gt;speecheditor&lt;/a&gt;, a web app for editing and adding musical scores to audio stories. Instead of editing speech using waveforms, the speecheditor allows you to edit audio with text, like a word processor. Likewise, it allows users to easily loop musical tracks and add &lt;a href=&quot;http://vis.berkeley.edu/papers/underscore&quot;&gt;musical underlays&lt;/a&gt; à la This American Life. The speecheditor is described in detail in our paper, &lt;a href=&quot;http://vis.berkeley.edu/papers/audiostories&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Content-based Tools for Editing Audio Stories.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speecheditor is research code. To that extent, this release is a polished prototype &amp;ndash; there are bound to be bugs that arise (please file those on the github issues page!) but we&amp;#39;ve had a lot of fun editing audio stories with this system and we believe it&amp;#39;s a powerful paradigm for DAWs of the future. We&amp;#39;re excited to have other creators try it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Browsers, Mechanical Turk, and external HITs</title>
			<link href="https://ssrubin.com/posts/browsers-mturk-and-external-hits.html"/>
			<updated>2013-11-13T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>https://ssrubin.com/posts/browsers-mturk-and-external-hits.html</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of experiments running on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mturk.com&quot;&gt;Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; this summer as ExternalHITs. In MTurk parlance, this means that the tasks were hosted on my research group&amp;#39;s server and embedded in Mechanical Turk via an &lt;code&gt;iframe&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started posting tasks again recently, and my external HITs were no longer working. Chrome was blocking the content, because mturk is https and my external content was running on http. Thanks to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.bcs.rochester.edu/HlpLab/MTurkExperiments&quot;&gt;U Rochester site&lt;/a&gt; for steering me in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; If your external HITs mysteriously stop working on Mechanical Turk (or if it seems like many fewer people are doing your hits than before), blame it on  updated browsers and their &lt;s&gt;draconian&lt;/s&gt; new security settings, and start serving https content from your server.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>A web-first research methodology</title>
			<link href="https://ssrubin.com/posts/web-first.html"/>
			<updated>2013-04-25T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>https://ssrubin.com/posts/web-first.html</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I started grad school in the Fall of 2011, I didn&amp;#39;t consider
myself to be an excellent programmer or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;hacker&lt;/a&gt; or anything
like that. On the other hand, I did consider myself to be an
exceptional googler and &lt;a href=&quot;http://hci.stanford.edu/research/opportunistic/&quot;&gt;tinkerer&lt;/a&gt;; I could usually scrounge
up a solution to my current programming problem without much
difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first research project in grad school involved a javascript-heavy
experiment that we were going to deploy to Mechanical Turk. I had done
my fair share of tinkering with client-side (HTML/CSS) and server-side
(Rails) web development, but I had always avoided javascript. No, I
don&amp;#39;t know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eager to show my collaborators that I was capable of writing code that
worked and writing it quickly, I dove into javascript&amp;#39;s prototypical
deep end. My code, hideous as it was, worked fine and allowed for
rapid iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to expand on the aforementioned hideousness, we&amp;#39;re talking a
whole mess of global variables and inline HTML:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs javascript&quot;&gt;$(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'body'&lt;/span&gt;).prepend(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'&amp;lt;span id=&quot;codespan&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Enter your code: &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;input style=&quot;display: inline&quot; id=&quot;turkcode&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;turkcode&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/input&amp;gt;&amp;lt;button id=&quot;codebutton&quot;&amp;gt;Submit&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;'&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh dear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intention isn&amp;#39;t to call out how bad I was at javascript a year and
half ago. I was inspired by the process. That project necessitated
that I build a web app, but my projects since then have been more
flexible. But all of my (and your, I&amp;#39;m guessing) research
collaborators have a somewhat unbelievable number of devices that can
access the web, so ideally, my research should live on the web instead
of in some C++ or Java code that may not ever be compiled on anyone
else&amp;#39;s machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of web-first research manifests itself it a number of ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever I&amp;#39;m building an interface, I will try to make it a web app
as opposed to a native GUI.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote collaborators can see what I&amp;#39;m working on without
downloading and compiling code, getting the proper libraries
installed, debugging platform-specific issues, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone wants scientists to release their code. Once published,
web-based projects are easy to disseminate because they&amp;#39;re already
running in-browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each project, I maintain a private website to track progress,
results, and ideas. If someone misses a meeting, they can just check
the site to see what&amp;#39;s going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like learning new programming languages and frameworks. The web is
constantly evolving, so I have the opportunity to learn and extend
tons of cool web-related technologies and tools. So far in grad
school: &lt;a href=&quot;http://webpy.org/&quot;&gt;web.py&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/&quot;&gt;flask&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.djangoproject.com/&quot;&gt;django&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sqlalchemy.org/&quot;&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dojotoolkit.org/&quot;&gt;dojo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jquery.com/&quot;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jqueryui.com/&quot;&gt;jQuery UI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://underscorejs.org/&quot;&gt;underscore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeescript.org/&quot;&gt;coffeescript&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docpad.org&quot;&gt;docpad&lt;/a&gt; and many more. Being able to learn these tools while
I&amp;#39;m doing my research is a highly-motivational mixture of work and
play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rapid iteration for the web is, well, rapid. This applies to high-
level languages in general. Sure, algorithms are going to run a bit
slower, but only invest the time in highly optimized implementations
if your research depends on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web-first research doesn&amp;#39;t make sense for all areas of research, but I
encourage other graduate students (HCI and otherwise) to think about
these things as they&amp;#39;re working on projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Site redesign</title>
			<link href="https://ssrubin.com/posts/redesign.html"/>
			<updated>2013-04-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>https://ssrubin.com/posts/redesign.html</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m working on an (admittedly simple) redesign of my site. I may
change things significantly from this form because&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am indecisive, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One obvious difference is that there is a section here for &amp;quot;posts.&amp;quot;
I&amp;#39;m not sure exactly what&amp;#39;s going to become of this section. I might
end up scrapping it in the future. But for now, it&amp;#39;s here. I have a
soft spot for blogging. When I first purchased this domain when I was
in 7th grade, I wrote a blog that was horribly written and often
banal, but my friends kept reading, so I kept writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a graduate student, I probably have more interesting things to say
now than I did back then. Probably.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
</feed>